# Ben Sharp

# Freelance Web Development

Flat 22, The Mill Apartments 1-7 Mill Lane London, NW61AQ 07590075001 bfwsharp@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Hello! I'm Ben, a creative, freelance web developer with 9 years experience specialising in front-end technologies namely JavaScript to ES6, HTML and CSS. I am passionate about building effective, user friendly web experiences.

After spending several years working in a freelance capacity, I've realised that as a result of the continuously changing requirements of my various clients, I needed to constantly shift the focus of my work. I have reached a stage now where I want a role where I can apply my energy in a more focused manner and build up my skills in the front-end where my passion lies.

I am now looking to join an organisation full time that will help me to achieve these goals.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### International Railway Journal, Cornwall UK - Freelance

January 2017 - Present

- Providing consultation, project management and support for company's subscription based industry data visualisation application.
- Diagnosing and rectifying issues
- Adding to and developing new application features
- Provided SSL security
- Providing managed hosting service

Tech stack: HTML | CSS/SASS | JS | jQuery | AngularJS | PHP | ExpressionEngine | Vagrant | Bootstrap | Trello

# Your Favourite Story, London UK - Freelance

May - June 2017

- Joined the agency interactive team to develop a point of sale touch table application for Mercedes-Benz UK showrooms in vanilla JS using bespoke in house framework.
- Worked closely with project management and design team to deliver in a tight timeframe.
- Made amends and bug fixes to various other Mercedes-Benz platforms.

Tech stack: HTML | CSS/SASS | JS | jQuery | JSON | GreensockJS | SVG | HandlebarsJS | Bootstrap | Bitbucket | JIRA | Sketch

#### Antidote, London UK - Freelance

November 2014 - Present

- Lead the development of multiple agency web projects.
- Provided digital consultation and support

Tech stack: AS2/3 | Photoshop | Illustrator | HTML | CSS/SASS/LESS | JS | jQuery | Gulp | Webpack | GreensockJS | SVG | Bootstrap | GitHub | PHP | Wordpress | Ink for Emails

#### ThirtyThree, London UK - Freelance

January - November 2014

- Built multiple websites using custom in house CMS.
- Developed numerous sliders, quizzes and video player modules.
- Performed on going maintenance and updates to agency client websites

Tech stack: HTML | CSS/SASS | JS | jQuery | JSON | XML | PHP | Concrete5 | Bootstrap | Mercurial | Bitbucket

## Everywhere, London UK - Freelance

October - December 2013

- Developed a scrolling parallax visual product showcase for Virgin Atlantic's new Dreamliner 787.
- Major site functionality updates to an ecommerce Wordpress build.
- HTML Email campaigns.

Tech stack: HTML | CSS | JS | jQuery | JSON | PHP | Wordpress + ACF | Bootstrap | Trello

#### Cool Square, London UK - Freelance

August - September 2013

 Responsive build for central London luxury apartments with ExpressionEngine backend. <a href="https://www.196bishopsgate.com">www.196bishopsgate.com</a>

Tech stack: HTML | CSS | JS | PHP | Foundation | ExpressionEngine

#### VCCP, London UK - Freelance

April - June 2013

- Developed a tongue in cheek animated left to right scrolling quiz for the Telegraph newspaper, celebrating '20 years of Clarkson'.
- Users were asked to demonstrate their knowledge of Clarkson's history through an animated journey, where they received a score at the end.

Tech stack: HTML | CSS | JS | jQuery | XML

# The Minimart, London UK - Creative Web Developer

November 2008 - March 2013

- Built client websites, games, banner campaigns
- Worked closely with managing director in pitching for new business
- Maintained performance of existing client websites
- Maintained agency I.T infrastructure
- Lead the development of agency website

Tech stack: Flash | AS2/3 | Greensock | HTML | CSS | JS | jQuery | XML | JSON | PHP | Photoshop | Illustrator | TortoiseSVN | Doubleclick | cPanel | Plesk

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Qantm (University of Middlesex), London - Diploma

2006 - 2008

Web design and development.

# University of Brighton, East Sussex - HND

2003 - 2005

Computer science.

Java, mathematics, set-theory, GUI-design, hardware.

#### Impington College International Sixth Form - A Level

2000 - 2002

Drama, English, Media Studies (B, C, D)

# Impington Village College - GCSE

1995 - 2000

10 GCSE grades A-C

#### **REFERENCES**

Available from long term direct clients and agencies upon request.